Guide to the Charles D. Wrege Hawthorne Studies Research Data 1882-1974
Charles D. Wrege Hawthorne Studies Research Data
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Charles D. Wrege Hawthorne Studies Research Data,
1882-1974
5167
Wrege, Charles D.
8.5 linear ft.
Articles, reprints, pamphlets, correspondence.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related Collections:
5618: Charles D. Wrege Research Papers Regarding History of Management
6012 AV: Charles D. Wrege Collection of Audio-Visual Materials
6304: Charles Wrege, Collector. Midvale Steel Company index cards, 1867-1930
6118 AV: Kheel AV Collection.
6012m: Wrege, Charles D. "Facts and Fallacies of Hawthorne." Doctoral Dissertation. 1961.
6014: Wrege, Charles D., Collector. History of Management Documents.
5618 P: Charles D. Wrege History of Management Collection of Midvale Steel Company Photographs
6054: Wrege, Charles D., Collector. Additional Taylor Charts, 1908-1944.
5167: Charles D. Wrege Hawthorne Studies Research Data
6014 P: Charles D. Wrege Collection of History of Management Photographs
6271: Wrege, Charles D., Collector. International Management Institute (IMI). Correspondence.
6013 P: Charles D. Wrege Collection of Midvale Steel Company Photographic Negatives
Series: LIST
Series: Data on Factory Lighting before 1919, leading to the Hawthorne Studies
Series: William Durgin
Series: Lighting 1919
Series: Lighting 1920
Series: Dolphin
Series: Lighting 1921
Series: Lighting 1922
Series: Detroit Piston Ring, Timken Test, Lighting 1924
Series: National Research Council (NRC) & Illumination Tests
Series: National Research Council (NRC) - Edison Data 1924-27
Series: National Research Council (NRC) - Atmosphere & Man Study
Series: W.F. Supply Dept., W.E. Hawthorne Data - 1905-1965, G.E. & NRC
Series: Chase E. Snow
Series: Men on CIL
Series: Men in Illum. Tests, John Mudroch Correspondence
Series; Franke
Series: Correspondence with Samuel Hibben
Series: Maurice Holland Correspondence
Series: Correspondence with Edwin Layton
Series: Theodore K. Quinn Correspondence
Series: Correspondence with John Scott
Series: Thomas A. Edison and Hawthorne Studies
Series: 1924-1925 Tests
Series: Temperature - Humidity, 1924-25, Hawthorne, Snow "Log"
Series: Geiss - Allphin
Series: 1925 Light Data
Series; Whittemore
Series: 1926-1927 tests
Series: "Data on Special Illumination Test" (1927) or "Moonlight Test"
Series: Sidebotham
Series: Dennison Test
Series: Bridgeport
Series: Atkins Test
Series: Whiting-Davis
Series: Snow Outline of Final Report on the National Research Council (NRC), 1928
Series: 1927-1930 Light Data
Series: Lighting 1930-1965
Series: R.H. Frazier Hawthorne Experiments 1928-29
CONTAINER LIST
- Photocopy and original of color guide to C.D. Wrege files. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  See: Box 17, ff. 2-4 Copies of Original Reports and Correspondence Related to the Hawthorne Illumination Tests
- Series: Data on Factory Lighting before 1919, leading to the Hawthorne Studies
  - Page 69 and 70 from The Society of Gas Lighting (1887) on Edison Electric Illuminating Company (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Gas Lighting in New York City (Box 1, Folder 3)
    empty folder
  - 1. Gas light and Experimental and Tungsten lighting (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 2. 3-types of Gas Light Street Lamps (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Gas Light Advertisements (Box 1, Folder 4)
    photocopies of three
  - Arthur A. Bright, The Electric Lamp Industry (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1906 Lamp Report of Lamp Committee of the Association of Edison Illuminating Companies (TAEIC) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    "on improvement of carbon filament lamps since 1881 (Hand written)
  - Photographs of gas lighting in New York City (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Taken from a book - not orginals
  - Portion of Western Electric Magazine - "Philadelphia Story", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    July/Aug. 1963 - on Old Western Electric photos at 300 E. Allegheny Ave. Bldg
  - 14th Bulletin E.E.L.C.(?) on "Isolated Plants", 1882 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    says 17th; 10/14/82 - handwritten
  - Data from: Arthur A. Bright Jr. The Electric Lamp Industry (1949), MacMillan Co. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence w/ Judson Dickerman on Hawthorne Studies, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    friend of Cooke
  - Data on American Institute of Electrical Engineer's (pgs 187 - 192) and p. 193 on National Electric Lamp Association (NELA) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    No date - assume late 1800's
  - Talk by Mr. T. Carpenter Smith (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - One sheet - Oberlin Smith, American Institute of Electrical Engineers (A.I.E.E.) on "Lighting Factories", 1895 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Vol 12, (pp. 323- 324)
  - Notes on Streetlighting, 1900-1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    handwritten
  - W.B. Thompson, "commercial experience with NERNST & MERIDIAN LAMPS", and the Association of Edison Illuminating Companies (A.E.I.C.), 1903 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    pp. 107-108, (handwritten)
  - Misc. data on the Kern Incandescent Gas Light Company, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - J.R. Cravath "Do We Need Better Illuminating Engineering" Western Society of Engineers, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Vol. X, #5 (Sept - Oct 1905) pp. 639-659 (Heading same as piece of paper inside folder, i.e. just contains citation not the article itself.)
  - Data on Illuminating Engineering Society & Industrial Lights, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    one sheet
  - Data on Incandescent lamps, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    1/2 sheet
  - Wm. D'Ryan on Production & Lighting, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    T.I.E.S. Vol 1, #5 June 1906, p.22
  - Alfred Spice New York City (N.Y.C.) Report on Lamps in Plainfield N.J. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Preston S. Miller, Lamp Renewal Policies, Association of Edison Illuminating Companies (A.E.I.C.), 1908 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Factory Gas Light, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Alex Dow, on "Camp Renewals", Association of Edison Illuminating Companies (A.E.I.C.), 1908 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    p.19 (one sheet)
  - Light: Its Use & Misuse, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Booklet by Illuminating Engineering Society (IES)
  - Chas. Russell, "Promising Fields for Development of Central Station Business", Association of Edison Illuminating Companies (A.E.I.C.), 1912 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Minutes
  - Copies of Electric City Magazine with articles by W.A. Durgin on "simple methods of Good Lighting", 1912 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Published by Samuel Insull's Commonwealth Edison Co. of Chicago
  - Samuel Insull on General Electric (G.E.) & Lamp Renewals, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    (A.I.E.C.) Minutes, pp. 235-238
  - 2) Lighting Journal, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    April 1913, Welsbach Street Lighting Co. of America
  - 1) Lighting Journal, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    April 1913, Penna. Globe Gas Light Co.
  - Advertisement on Gas Lighting (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Welsbach gas lighting advertisements in Lighting Journal, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    December 1913 (empty folder)
  - Report of the Committee on Indoor Lighting, National Commercial Gas Association (NCGA), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    pp.325-346 one sheet of notes
  - C. Willing Hare, "Presidents Address", National Commercial Gas Association (NCGA), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    on proposal to merge American Gas Institute and National Commercial Gas Association (AGI & NCGA) into the Gas Institute
  - Thomas W. Rolph, "Metal Reflectors for Industrial Lighting", 1913 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    T.I.E.S., May 16, 1913, pp. 281-83 on prod. & lighting
  - Gas Lighting, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    National Commercial Gas Association (NCGA) - 2 sheets of notes
  - 1) Norman MacBeth "gas lighting in U.S." (Box 1, Folder 36)
    p. 971
  - 4) R.E. Simpson (Illumination & Saftey) (Box 1, Folder 36)
    p. 463,464
  - 2) C.W. Jordan "Recent Advances in Gas Lighting", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Ties 1914, p. 873-894
  - 3) Clarence E. Clewell on "Factory Lighting" (Box 1, Folder 36)
    p. 471
  - Commonwealth Edison Lamp Renewals in Electrical World, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    May 9, 1914, pp. 1054-1055 - notes
  - 1914 Street Lighting Tests (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Notes
  - Photos of Gas Lights (Box 1, Folder 39)
    ARC type for factories; Amer. Gas Light Co. one print
  - Edward P. Hyde, "Progress in the Science of Lighting", 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Public Utility Economics, West Side YMCA, New York Public Library, TNH (call letters)
  - J.W. Lieb "The Supply of Incandescent Lamps to Central Station Customers.", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Oct. 2, 1914 - Typed copy - 8 pages - carbon
  - Report of Committee on Street Lighting, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    A.E.I.C. Minutes on Vaughn & Sweet and Milwaukee Lighting (one sheet)
  - Data from 1916 street - lighting tests on Intervale Avenue, Bronx, New York City (Box 2, Folder 1)
    2 pgs. Handwritten
  - Sweet "Street Lighting Developments at Milwaukee" (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Notes 1 pg.
  - Nat'l. Electric Lamp Assoc. & Bulletin of the Engineering Dept on "Industrial Lighting", 1916 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    NELA #4, 1/14/07, 1916 p. 124 (1 pg. note)
  - C.E. Clewell - New Lighting Codes for Factories, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Electric Journal, Vol. 13
  - Information on Productivity & Illumination, 1916-1917 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Lighting Journal (notes 4 pgs.)
  - M. Luckiesh, The Lighting Art, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    McGraw - Hill; 1pg. pencil notes
  - "Program for Limitation of the Production and Distribution of inefficient carbon & Gem Lamps", 1918 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Sept. 1918 (empty folder)
  - Correspondence with State of Illinois on Henkle - Best Company on Factry lyte, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    one letter
  - Edwin D. Tillson (Commonwealth Edison) Patent #1,360,825 for Industrial Fixture, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Factry lyte. Notes and Correspondence
  - Material in letter books at Englehard Industries Newark, N.J. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Series: William Durgin
  - Correspondence on Commonwealth Edison Illumination Tests, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Durgin
  - John W. Lieb "Notes for Presentation Before Electrical Conductor Dealers, July 2, 1918" (Box 2, Folder 12)
    11 pgs - thermofax
  - Summary of Early Illumination Tests, 1918-1931 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - William Durgin, photographs of test locations for illumination tests, 1918-1919 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Envelope does Not contain photos, rather handwritten notes on Durgin, 1919 (lots of notes) - photos with C. D. Wrege dissertation pages
  - Results of Lee - Loader & Body Company test results, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    notes
  - Durgin - 1930 Annual Report of the Dir. of Research, Utilities Research Commissions, Personnel List and other correspondence 1921, 1921- 1930 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - William A Durgin, Envelope from Mrs. Durgin (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence with Secretary of State of Illinois on: Lee Loader and Body Co. (1917), Stromberg Motor Devices (1907), Utilities Research Commission (1930), 1907-1930 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Durgin in Tests - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence with Commonwealth Edison Co. on Tillson, Millan, Durgin, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - William Durgin File, corres., and notes, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Information on William Durgin - on Early Industrial Lighting Tests, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Reports by Durgin and also corres. (1959) between Wrege and Durgin's wife
  - Durgin "Early Papers" E-1, E-2, 1909-1910 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Durgin "Later Papers" Lp-1, Lp-2, 1924-1931 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Wm. Durgin (Original Material) - Newspaper clippings - etc. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Department of Commerce Job materials and Corres. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Durgin, "Sent Back List", List M-1 - M-15 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Series: Lighting 1919
  - Forrest McDonald, letters etc. on Pfister & Vogel, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Milwaukee 1912 or 1919 study
- Series: Lighting 1920
  - Factory Lighting Legislation in Great Britain, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    (? his not ours)
  - O.R. Hogue & J.F. Kirk - "Factory Lighting - a Central Station Problem", 1920 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Transactions I.E.S. (TIES) (Feb. 10, 1920, p. 46-60) with data on Durgin
  - R.O. Eastman, "A Survey of Industrial Lighting Conditions", 1920 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Transactions I.E.S. (TIES) (Feb. 10, 1920), Vol. XV, No. 1, pp. 77-88 - notes
  - Data on Ward Harrisons speech at Rochester, New York, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    May 7, 1920 (1 page note)
  - Data on Ward Harrisons talk on Lighting, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    12/12/1920, Transactions I.E.S. (TIES) (Nov. 20, 1920) p. 111, (1 page note)
  - J.B. Wilson "Central Station Experience on the Improvement of Factory Lighting", 1920 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    I.E.S., Vol XV, Nov. 20, 1920 (pp. 582- 586) notes
  - Ward Harrison, on "Industrial Lighting" in his book: Electric Lighting, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    American Technical Society, Chicago Ill. - 1920 p. 146-160 - notes
  - Ward Harrison " The RLM Standard Reflector for Industrial Lighting", 1920 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    I.E.S., Vol. 15 #6, Aug. 30, 1920, notes
  - Bassett Jones on "illumination & production", 1920 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Data on W.J. Drisko & S.G. Hibben, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Ties, Vol. 15 #9 Dec. 30, 1920, p. 125
  - Electric Lighting in The 20's (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with Boston Edison Co. on NRC, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Series: Dolphin
  - C.D. Wrege - Correspondence on Dolphin Jute Mills, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Paterson, N.J. [for Hawthorne Illumination Tests]
- Series: Lighting 1921
  - Information on Lighting Campaign in Cleveland, OH, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Photograph of (15) automobiles used in Cleveland Electric Light Campaign, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    original
  - S.D. Heed, Wiring Old Residences in Cincinnati, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    July 18, 1921 - copy
  - Correspondence on Ivanhoe - Regency Works, G.E., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence with Taylor Instrument Companies, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Charles E. Blood, "Gas Lighting and the Business Field", 1921 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    American Gas Journal (March 5, 1921, pp. 203-204, and 213) - 1p. of notes
  - Boston Industrial Lighting Exhibit, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    1) July 1921 Vol.8 #7. 2) Nov. 1921, Vol.8 #11. NELA Bulletin 1) p.418 2) p.649, 650 - all notes
  - Data on Industrial Lighting in Electric Journals, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "Reflectors for Incandescent Lamps", 1921 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Booklet by Edison Lamp Works, April 1921
  - "Industrial Lighting", 1921 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    from various sources - notes
- Series: Lighting 1922
  - Data on industrial lighting in electric journals, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Cleveland Campaign material, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    originals
  - R.L.M. Standards Institute Data (Box 3, Folder 25)
    list
  - National Electric Light Association (NELA) Jt. Committee for Business Development, Electrify Magazine Guide Book, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Theodore K. Quinn (on Mazda Lamps & Jobbers), 1919 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    notes on
  - Robert Ffrench Pierce, "Factory Lighting", 1918 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    as reported in American Gas Engineering Journal, April 6, 1918, pp.224-228 - notes
  - Chas O. Bond "Report of the Illumination Committee", 1919 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    (with Statistics of Gas Lighting), American Gas Association [first annual convention, Oct. 13-18, 1919 N.Y.C.] (pp. 224-228), notes
  - National Electric Light Association (N.E.L.A.) on "Residence Lighting", 1919 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    pp.147-149 - notes
  - "Economic Aspects of Ind. Lighting", 1919 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    C.E. Clewell (professor of Electric Engineering, Univ. of PA)
  - Industrial Lighting, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    General Electric (G.E.) National Lamp Works, Bulletin #36 May 19, 1919 (original document)
  - Advertisements of the Mississippi Wire Glass Co. in Tech Engineering News, M.I.T., Cambridge, MA, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Information on Industrial Lighting in Electric Journals, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - J.J. Kirk & W.E. Underwood, "Store Lighting & Industrial Lighting", 1923 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    National Electric Light Association (NELA) Bulletin Feb. 1923 Vol.X #2 notes on
  - "Improvements in Street Lighting", 1923 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Technical Engineering News, May 1923, Vol.IV #2 p.54 under "Monthly News" - notes on
  - "The Years' Progress in Illumination", 1923 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Transactions I.E.S. (TIES), Sept. 1923, p.587 on origin of the word Gas - notes on
  - Transactions I.E.S. (T.I.E.S.) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Data on Industrial lighting, Glassteel Diffusers, and "Good Lighting & Prosperity", 1923 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    M. Luckiesh (with notes)
  - Data on Heating Research Committee, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Association of Edison Illuminating Companies (A.E.I.C.) (8 pgs. carbon copy)
- Series: Detroit Piston Ring, Timken Test, Lighting 1924
  - Clarence Law & Illuminating Engineering Society (IES) / National Research Council (NRC), 1924 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Thermafax copies
  - Factory Lighting in Periodicals, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Notes on various articles
  - Data on Industrial Lighting in Electric Journals, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Advertisement on Tungsten Lamp - Electric Light & Power, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Advertisements in the Technical Engineering News of the Mississippi Wire Glass Co., 1924 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Street Lighting, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Preston Millar (from Elec. Light & Power, 1924) [original]
  - John W. Lieb, "Good Lighting by American Central Stations", 1924 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Transactions I.E.S. (T.I.E.S.) Sept. 1924, Vol.XIV p.629 on National Research Council (NRC), July 1924 (typed notes)
  - Correspondence with various Electric Light Companies on illumination tests: 1)Consumer's Power Co. Jackson MI on Jackson Corset Co. Test, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Series: National Research Council (NRC) & Illumination Tests
  - C.D. Wrege - correspondence with National Research Council on Hawthorne Illumination tests, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Data on Hawthorne Illumination tests (Box 4, Folder 16)
    in Annual Reports of the National Academy of Sciences (with exclusive dates and pages)
  - Data on Engineering Foundation, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    [pamphlet #2, Feb. 1925]
  - Pamphlet on Division of Engineering of National Research Council (NRC), 1922 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    (Sept. 1922) 36pp. - 1 page note
  - National Research Council Data in NY Times, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    1 page note
  - Proceedings of National Research Council (NRC), 1921-1926 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    (on origin etc.) notes on
  - National Archives on National Research Council (NRC) (Box 4, Folder 21)
    correspondence with
  - Initiation of National Research Council (NRC) Tests, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Illuminating Engineering Society (I.E.S.) Feb. 1924, Vol.XIX, #2, pp.125-134 (notes on)
  - Data on Hawthorne Tests in Transactions of the Illuminating Engineering Society, 1922-1928 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - C.I.L. in Annual Report N.A.S. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    typed note
  - [A Report of] George Hoxie Stickney on Revision of Lighting of Thomas A.(T.A.) Edisons Library, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Transactions of the Illuminating Engineering Society (T.I.E.S.) Vol.XX #8 (Oct. 1925) p.858
  - Correspondence with Dr. George S. Crampton on Hawthorne Studies, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence on Dean Seahore (Box 4, Folder 27)
    [in Connection with C.I.L.] (empty folder)
  - Correspondence with R.G. Stansfield on Hawthorne, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    [Dept. of Scientific & Ind. Research, London] [Dec. 22, 1957]
  - Dugald C. Jackson. Photo. (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Dugald C. Jackson. Articles and Booklet, 1889-1928 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    1889, 1897, 1928, note on
  - Letter from Dr. Ives to Dugald C. Jackson, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    11/9/25. Notes and correspondence on
  - Correspondence with Dugald C. Jackson Jr., 1957 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dugald C. Jackson Data for: 1889, 1911 and letters from Nebraska State Historical Society, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Maurice Holland on the National Research Council (NRC) and Hawthorne, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Leland Franke on Hawthorne Illumination Tests, 1957-1964 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cheney Bros. Corp., 1958 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Unlabeled folder - contents cover 1958
  - Study on Hawthorne Illumination test [Jackson etc.] by Steve Rusnick of Kearny Works of Western Electric, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Series: National Research Council (NRC) - Edison Data 1924-27
  - Illuminating Engineering Society (I.E.S.) Data at Edison Archives, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    compiled 9/17/58
  - Data on Edison National Historic Site, 1957-1964 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - List of documents, Edison Archives on Nation Research Council Committee on Industrial Lighting, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Charles D. Wrege (Aug. 22, 1957) 6 pages - 5 copies
  - Folder #1 containing letters 1-5 on Edison as Chairman of C.I.L., 1924 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    2/27/1924 to 5/9/1924 (empty folder)
  - correspondence from Maurice Holland, Dir. Division of Engineering & Industrial Research to W.H. Meadowcroft, Asst. to Thomas A. Edison, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    May 29, 1924 (unlabeled folder)
  - outline of correspondence on outside of folder (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Empty folder, no heading, outline of correspondence on outside of folder
  - outline of correspondence on outside of folder (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - outline of correspondence on outside of folder (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - outline of correspondence on outside of folder (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Letter from Edison Lab. on My Hawthorne findings, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    7/1/1957
  - pamphlet on Edison Laboratory: Edison Laboratory National Monument, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    U.S. Govt. 1957 - O - 437438
  - Letter from Edison Lab. to Rutgers, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    9/10/1964
- Series: National Research Council (NRC) - Atmosphere & Man Study
  - Notes on 1914 N.Y. Ventilation Commission (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence with Taylor Instruments Company on Ellsworth Huntington, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    11/10/1959
  - Variations in efficiency in Cotton Weaving, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    (Ind. Fatigue Research Report #23, 1923) - notes on
  - Air Movement Tests (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - "Effect of Air Conditions on Physical Work", 1923 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    from: Report of N.Y. State Commission on Ventilation (E.P. Dutton, 1923), Table 29, p.88, notes on
  - Effect of Temperature, Humidity and Sunshine upon production, 1919-1920 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Series: W.F. Supply Dept., W.E. Hawthorne Data - 1905-1965, G.E. & NRC
  - Advertisement for National Lamp Works ["It speeds"] Factory, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    January 1925
  - "Better Lighting increases production 35% ", 1923 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    Earl Anderson (Electrical World, Vol. 8, #26, June 30, 1923)
  - Western Electric Advertisement in Light, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Oct. 1925, p.39; labeled for Data on Western Electric Supply Dept. but no data
  - Ward Harrison, patent #1,331,062 (illum measuring device), 1920 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Feb. 17, 1920 (empty folder)
  - Correspondence on RLM reflectors (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "Does Good Lighting Pay Its Way In Industrial Plants?", 1925 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Ward Harrison, Factory, June 1925, pp.932-33 (copies of photos)
  - Data on Gerard Swope, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    from David Loth's Book
  - "1920 - 1925 Lighting Campaign", 1941 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    General Electric Co. [data from U.S. vs. G.E. Civil Action #1364, 1941] (notes - 2 sheets, pencil)
  - Relationship between M.I.T. & G.E., 1920 (Box 6, Folder 6)